# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone.
# 今天这个灶 冰箱 打荷台都到了
The wok ranges, refrigerators, and kitchen workbenches have arrived today.
# 现在刚刚卸完货特别热
We just offloaded them, and it’s so hot today.
# 我们那个旧的灶可能有800多斤
The old range is about 800 jin (400 kg).
# 很难抬 七八个人抬着要轻松一点
It is so hard to move. Maybe it takes seven or eight people to lift it together.
# 我们今天只有5个人所以抬着比较累
But we only have 5 people here today so it was a strenuous task
# 现在就等师傅再拉一车过来 再卸完这个
Now we are waiting for another truck of stuff. And after offloading this,
# 然后就可以摆进去了 现在我们地板已经装好了
we could bring everything in and the floor is done already.
# 你看一下
Look at this,
# 冰箱 灶 打荷台都到了
The refrigerators, wok ranges, kitchen workbenches have all arrived.
# 我们砧板都换了 不用那个松木的现在用这个皂木的
We changed the cutting board. We got rid of the pine one and use the soapwood one now.
# 这个厚度是10公分的 直径应该是40多（厘米）接近50厘米
This one is about 10cm high, and about 50cm wide,
# 有五六十斤吧这个
about 50 to 60 jin (25-30kg).
# 这个相对于松木来说木质更硬一些 然后不容易发霉
Compared to the pine cutting board, this one is harder and less prone to mold.
# 但是颜色花纹可能没有那么好看
But the pattern may not look so pretty.
# 然后就是比松木要耐用一点 贵也要贵很多
And this one lasts longer than pine wood, and much more expensive.
# 这个的花纹要更好看一些
The pattern on this one looks better.
# 因为它这个芯在这个地方 这一台的话它的芯偏了一点点
Because the middle point is right here, but it is a little bit off on this one.
# 偏了大概5公分左右 所以就没有这个那么好
It is off for about 5 cm, so not as perfect.
# 现在我们这个灶跟以前的灶有一点不太一样
And this cooking stove is a bit different from the one we used to have.
# 现在这个是主气 这个是火种
This one uses gas and this one uses fire.
# 然后这里有一个风门开关
and there is a fan switch here.
# 所以就不用另外去接一个开关 现在这个很方便
so you don’t have to connect another switch. This is so convenient.
# 然后这里还有一个这个打开
Here is another thing. You can open it,
# 上面可以流水下来洗这个灶
Water flows down and you can use it to clean the range.
# 自动清洗这个叫
This is called an auto cleaner.
# 而且现在这种灶大概只有600多斤吧
and this range is only about 600 jin(300kg).
# 然后我们以前的 比如说后面这一台灶大概有800多斤
and the old ones, like the one in the back is about 800 jin(400 kg),
# 要重很多
which is much heavier.
# 现在我们就把灶抬进来
Now we move the ranges in.
# 然后等到明天的时候水电工过来把这里的线 水接好之后
The plumber and the electrician will come tomorrow to set up the utilities
# 就把这个装上去
After that, we will build this up,
# 装上去了之后再撕这个膜
and then we tear the cover off,
# 撕完这个膜的话就基本上差不多了
After that, we are basically done.
# 再一个就是这个冰箱水电 还有排水系统这方面的
Another thing is water line and electricity for the refrigerators, as well as the drainage system.
# 大概搞这个要花3天左右吧
It could take about three days.
# 现在地板都已经铺好了
Now the floor is all done,
# OK
ok,
# 你这块板没有装好吧
Did you place this piece correctly?
# 锅没拿
Forgot to bring the pots.
# 你该给我拿几个锅撒
Could you bring me a few pots?
# 啊
Ahh,
# 至少都要拿2个锅
We need at least two woks.
# 锅啊 炒锅啊
Woks, like frying woks
# 我晓得
I know.
# 没拿过来
I didn’t bring them.
# 没写进去还是说
You didn’t write it down or what?
# 没写
I forgot to write it.
# 没写是吧
Didn’t write it down, right?
# 那你下单嘛 帮我下
Make the order for me, then.
# 店里有
We have them at the store,
# 店里有是吧
You have woks in the store?
# 有
Yes.
# 我就说好像少了一点什么东西这个灶上面
I knew there is something missing on the cooker.
# 原来是没有买锅
We forgot to buy woks.
# 要6个锅 还有炒勺 锅铲 还有那个宽油盆 漏勺之类的
We need six pots/woks, ladles, spatulas, containers for oil, strainers, etc.
# 今天我们这个就差不多了
That’s about it today.
# 3台灶 3个打荷台 2台冰箱 还有一个6眼的灶
Three jet burner ranges, three kitchen workbenches, two refrigerators, and a gas range with 6 burners.
# 这些最基本的东西已经进来了
All that basic stuff has arrived.
# 今天就先搞到这里 今天也搞累了
That‘s it for today. Everyone is tired.
# 光抬这些东西抬得腰酸背痛的
Lifting these things has caused back pain.
# 嗯 这些灶都很重
Yeah, all of them are heavy.
# 然后下一步就等着水电一装好
And the next step is to wait for the utilities to be set up.
# 然后就把其它的该买的一些零部件就全部给它一次性弄到位
Then we will buy some parts and finish everything one time.
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里 拜拜
Okay, that’s it for today’s video, bye-bye.